《生活大爆炸》前情提要
Previously on The Big Bang Theory
谢尔顿  你这是想出了一个办法
Sheldon, did you just figure out a method
可以人工合成一种新型稳定超重元素吗
for synthesizing a new stable super-heavy element?
是吗
Did I?
这不可能呀
Well, that can't be right.
从来没有人成功过呢
No one's ever done that before.
除了我  我想出来了
Except me, because I just did it!
谢尔顿谢尔顿脑力无边
Sheldon and his brain-- yeah!
谢尔顿谢尔顿脑震八方
我犯了个可怕的错误
I've made a horrible mistake.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
这个表格是平方厘米制的
This table-- it's in square centimeters.
我看成了平方米
I read it as square meters.
知道这意味着什么吗
You know what that means?
美国人看不懂公制吗
That Americans can't handle the metric system?
艾米  我这是失之毫厘差之千里的错误
Amy, I was off by a factor of 10,000.
但是中国研究小组发现了元素
But the Chinese team found the element.
他们不应该发现的
Yeah, well, they shouldn't have.
我的计算是错的
My calculations were wrong.
我这辈子最伟大的科学成就
the greatest scientific achievement of my life
是建立在一个巨大的错误之上
is based on a blunder.
我不是天才
I'm not a genius,
我是个骗子
I'm a fraud.
谢尔顿  在神经系统学里
You know, Sheldon, in neuroscience,
我们总是在大脑某处有所发现
we're forever finding something in one part of the brain
但地方和原来想的完全不一样
that we thought was someplace else.
这下可好  我连骗子都不如了
Oh, great, now I'm worse than a fraud.
我沦为生物学家之流了
I'm practically a biologist.
欢迎收听《科学星期五》  我是艾拉·菲莱
This is Science Friday. I'm Ira Flatow.
今日的来宾是第一个
My guest today is responsible for the discovery
稳定超重元素的发现者
of the first stable super-heavy element.
欢迎谢尔顿·库伯博士
Welcome, Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
谢谢
Thank you.
是学校硬要我来的
Uh, the university made me come here.
我本人并不想来
I didn't want to.
我是这节目的忠实听众哦
Uh, big fan of the show.
我听说你之所以发现这元素
So, I understand that you actually discovered
完全是因为一个错误
this element by mistake.
是的
Yes.
而科学界有些人把这个错误称之为
And some people in the science community are calling it
-"蠢货奇迹"  -那些人是谁
- "The Wonder Blunder." - Who?
告诉我他们的名字
Give me their names.
肯定是沃罗威茨
I bet it's Wolowitz.
这故事真是太了不起了
It's just such a fascinating story.
你在计算上偏差了这么多
Your calculations are way off,
却还是有人找到了这元素
but they find the element anyway.
感觉就像是读错藏宝地图
It's like misreading a treasure map
却还是找到了宝藏一样
and still finding the treasure.
我们能聊别的话题吗
Can we talk about something else?
你知道我会唱山歌吗
Do you know that I yodel?
那不错啊  但这发现有可能
That's interesting, but this could be taking you
让你获得诺贝尔奖
down the path toward a Nobel Prize.
而且是化学奖哦
And in chemistry, no less.
这种情况很少见吧
And wouldn't that be unusual?
因为你是物理学家
Because you're a physicist.
对对对  我将是获得诺贝尔化学奖的物理学家
Yes, yes, I'd be a physicist with a Nobel in chemistry.
大家快来笑我这个奇葩吧
Everyone laugh at the circus freak.
我不需要坐在这忍受你的羞辱  菲莱
You know, I don't need to sit here and take this, Flatow.
就是因为有你这种恶霸
It is because of bullies like you,
所以每天才会有越来越多的
every day more and more Americans
美国人转投看电视
are making the switch to television.
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
生活大爆炸
第七季  第十集
塞伯特校长  你为什么要凶我
President Seibert, I don't know why you're yelling.
是你叫我去上广播节目的
You're the one who made me go on the radio.
我以为那会是一场专业的科学访谈
I was expecting a professional science interview,
而不是被整人节目口无遮拦的主持人攻击
not an attack by some morning zoo shock jock.
如果学校这么缺钱
Well, if the university needs money so badly,
或许你该设立个脏话罚款筒赚钱
perhaps you should start a swear jar.
你这一串脏话够罚一块钱啊
That one's worth a dollar.
我知道你不喜欢上节目
I know you don't like it,
但是你每次去接受采访
but every time you do an interview,
都能提大学提高知名度
it raises the profile of the university.
高知名度就有高资助费
That translates to funding.
我又不是受训的卖艺猴子
Yeah, well, I'm not just some trained monkey
帮他们乞讨钱
dancing for coins.
你当然不是啦
Of course you're not.
那种猴子多讨人喜欢
People love trained monkeys.
你有什么好不开心的啊
How can you not be happy?
你又高又瘦又出名
You're tall, thin and famous.
天啊  我好嫉妒谢尔顿
Oh, my God, I'm jealous of Sheldon.
这些访谈估计还持续一段时间
Look, you're gonna be doing this stuff for a while.
你得找到习惯这些事的方法
You're just gonna have to find a way to get used to it.
但你们没人能懂我的心情
But none of you know what this is like.
自己悔恨不已的事却被人大肆赞扬
Being celebrated for something you wish you never did.
想必你没跟我一起去过狂欢节
Mmm... you clearly haven't been with me at Mardi Gras.
要暂停一下游戏来帮忙我打扫吗
Want to pause the video game and help me clean up?
我正在打扫啊
I am cleaning up.
打扫小丑对高谭市造成的破坏
Look at the mess the Joker made of Gotham City.
拜托  要来暂住的可是你的朋友
Come on, it's your friend who's coming to stay here.
拉杰是在印度长大的
Raj grew up in India.
相信我  比这更脏的他都见过
Trust me, he's seen worse.
华仔
Howie.
我保证这周接下来的日子我会帮忙
I promise I'll help out the rest of the week.
这周接下来的日子
The rest of the week?
你不是说就一两天吗
You said it was just gonna be a night or two.
但如果我直接跟你说住一周
Yeah, but if I told you a week,
-你会同意吗  -当然不会
- would you have said yes? - No!
所以我只好出此下策啦
Then you left me no choice.
我喜欢拉杰  但他这暂住也太久了吧
I love Raj, but that's a long time for a house guest.
但他的公寓整个楼都在除虫  没法住
I know, but they're tenting his building.
他也找不到能让带宠物的酒店
He can't find a hotel he likes that allows dogs.
他还带小桂子来啊
He's bringing Cinnamon?
待一整周呢
For a whole week!
有些人真是大惊小怪
The nerve of some people.
迎面而来的是羞愧号快车
Here comes the Embarrassment Express.
将会经过  骗子镇站
With stops at Fraudville...
蠢货奇迹山站
WonderBlunderberg...
以及堪萨斯城
and Kansas City.
只因这是运输交汇处
Because it's a hub.
谢尔顿  我能进来吧
Sheldon, can I come in?
-你有带饼干吗  -没有
- Do you have cookies? - No.
很好  我不配吃饼干  进来吧
Good. I don't deserve cookies. Come in.
-威尔...  -谢尔顿
- Wil...? - Hey, Sheldon.
好久不见
It's been a while.
你怎么来了
Why are you here?
艾米说你最近不开心
Amy said you were having a rough time,
我就想来开导开导你
and I thought maybe we could talk.
可以吗
Is that okay?
当然可以
Certainly.
虽然...
Although...
现在我就不开心
right now, I'm having a rough time
因为我房间现在有三个人
because there's three people in my room,
感觉跟迪斯科舞厅一样拥挤
and it's starting to feel like a discotheque.
谢尔顿  你说你不开心是因为
Sheldon, you said you were unhappy getting attention
人们都在关注让你悔恨不已的事
for something you wished you never did.
关于这事  我也有点经验
Yeah, I know a little something about that.
少来了  威尔
Oh, nonsense, Wil.
你的刷屏微博也没那么糟啦
Your endless tweets are not that bad.
我想起这么久不见他的原因了
I remember why it's been a while.
谢尔顿  我要说的是
Sheldon, I was actually talking
我小时候在星际迷航里演出的事
about when I was a kid on Star Trek.
你怎么会不喜欢因为出演该电影
How could you not like getting attention
而获得大家的关注呢
for playing Wesley Crusher?
你的角色很讨喜啊
You were wonderful.
一个全知全能记忆超强的男孩
A know-it-all boy genius with an eidetic memory.
谁对那个角色会没有代入感啊
Who couldn't relate to that?
不是每个人都这么想的
Well, not everybody felt that way.
很多人很讨厌那个角色
A lot of people really hated the character,
因此有些人也为此而讨厌我
and some of them hated me because of it.
我也曾接受过访谈
I would do interviews,
很多人都会嘲讽我
and people would be mean to me.
我也碰到这种事了
That just happened to me.
下次你想不出刷什么屏了
Next time you're stuck for a tweet,
欢迎你写一条艾拉·菲莱是混蛋的微博
feel free to say what a jerk Ira Flatow is.
谢尔顿  重点的是威尔能学会接受现实
Sheldon, the point is Wil learned to embrace that part of his life
然后更重要的东西迈进
and moved on to bigger and better things.
是啊  我现在是个作家
Yeah, I'm an author now,
经常公开演讲
I do public speaking,
我自己还出了一部关于桌游的网络剧
and I have my own web series about board games.
我们是要哄他开心  所以...
We're trying to cheer him up, so...
我只是想告诉你  曾有一段时间
I'm just saying that there was a time when I thought
我以为自己走不出那角色的阴影
I would never get out of Wesley Crusher's shadow.
但现在
But now,
那只是我完美人生中的一小章节
it's just one small part of a pretty great life,
我也很开心有过那些经历
and it's a part that I'm happy is there.
我明白你的意思
I do see what you're saying.
挺受用的
That helps.
那就好
Good.
你们俩个要留下来一起玩火车吗
Would you two like to stay and play trains with me?
-好  -可以啊
- Sure. - Okay.
太好了
Oh, great!
现在呢
Now...
我来操作控制器
I work the controls.
我来喊"请上车"
I say "All aboard",
你们俩安静坐着看就行了
you sit quietly and watch.
我能吹哨子吗
Can I blow the whistle?
你还是走吧
You should probably go.
你要在我家沙发上刷牙吗
You're gonna brush your teeth on my couch?
我是要刷小桂子的牙
No, I'm gonna brush Cinnamon's teeth.
何苦呢
Why bother?
她有一半的时间都是在舔屁眼
She spends half the time licking her butt.
另一半的时间是在舔我脸
And the other half licking my face.
所以我才要帮她刷牙
That's why I'm brushing her teeth.
抱歉  我回来晚了
Hey, guys. Sorry I'm so late.
你们吃完饭了吗
Did you already have dinner?
没  我们在等你
No, we were waiting for you.
你们真好
Aw, that's so sweet.
所以你今晚打算煮什么呢
Yeah. So what do you feel like making?
霍华德  这可怜的姑娘刚忙完回家
Howard, the poor thing just got home from work.
我先给你倒杯酒
Let me get you a glass of wine.
然后我来做晚餐
I'll cook dinner.
-拉杰  你可是客人  -没关系啦
- Oh, Raj, you're our guest. - Don't be silly.
快坐下  你看上去很累
Sit. You look like you've had a long day.
没事啦  她经常这样
No, she always looks like that.
因为她嫁了个傻逼
Because she married an idiot.
谢谢  拉杰
Thank you, Raj.
客气啥  就当是我感谢你们
Please, this is my way of thanking you
让我住在这里吧
for letting me stay here.
跟我们说说你今天过得怎么样
Now, tell us all about your day.
好的  首先我开会迟到了
Okay, um, well, first, I was late to a meeting
因为在路上堵车了
'cause I was stuck in traffic.
我就叫你在手机装一个交通实时监控软件嘛
Well, I keep telling you to put that traffic app on your phone.
你今天回家抱怨  因为吃太多糖豆
Hey, when you got home today complaining that you felt sick
而肚子不舒服时
from eating too many jelly beans,
我有教你怎么解决问题吗
did I tell you how to fix it?
没有
No.
相反  我说"小可怜  一定很疼吧"
I said, "Aw, that must hurt,"
然后帮你揉肚肚
and I rubbed your belly.
我全程都在想着你
I thought of you the whole time.
我的意思是  有时你只需去倾听
All I'm saying is there's a time to just listen.
多谢
Thank you.
有时你也得适可而止  别吃那么多糖豆
There's also a time to stop eating too many jelly beans.
"有时"是指十岁以后
And it's when you're ten.
塞伯特校长
Hello, President Siebert.
谢谢您接听我的电话
Thank you for taking my call.
我只是想让您知道  您现在可以指望我
I just wanted you to know that you can now expect
热心参与有关我的发现的一切活动了
enthusiastic participation from me regarding my discovery.
不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no, no.
无需感谢我
No need to thank me.
要谢就谢我的朋友  威尔·惠顿
Thank my friend, Wil Wheaton.
向您报告一下  我有九个朋友
For your information, I have nine friends, hmm?
算上您的话  就十个
Ten if we include you.
那就九个吧
Nine it is.
还是十个吧  算上沃罗威茨好了
Ah, it's ten. I'll count Wolowitz.
你好  朋友莱纳德
Hello, friend Leonard.
你心情不错嘛
Hey, you're in a good mood.
我心情超棒的
I'm in a great mood.
那你的心情即将变得更棒
Well, you're about to be in an even better one.
我是现在确定了才敢告诉你
I didn't want to say anything until I knew for sure,
但
but...
我在我实验室重新测试了你的元素
I've been re-running the tests on your element in my lab
我证明了它不存在
and I disproved it.
你的元素根本不存在
Your element does not exist!
是吗  但中国的研究小组呢
Yeah, but what about the Chinese research team?
他们的确发现了啊
They found it.
结果证明是有人在
Yeah, it turns out someone added
数据文件里加入了模拟信号
simulated signals to the data files.
他们伪造了结果
They faked the results.
-真的吗  -真的
- Really? - Yes!
你知道这意味着什么吗
Do you know what that means?
你讨厌的所有关注  通通都会消失
That means all of this attention that you hate goes away.
所以不会再有访问吗
So no more interviews?
对  全都结束了
No, it's all over.
真是难以置信
I can't believe it.
不用客气
Well, you're welcome.
你夺走了我这辈子最大的成就
You robbed me of my greatest achievement!
什么
What?!
我现在只有九个朋友了
I'm back down to nine friends!
算了  八个吧  我也不喜欢沃罗威茨
Make it eight-- I'm sick of Wolowitz, too!
我不明白了
I-I don't understand.
自从你发现这个该死的元素后
All you've done since you discovered
你就一直在抱怨个不停
this stupid element was complain.
我只是想让你开心
I was trying to make you happy!
所以要夺走我唯一成名的机会吗
By taking away my only claim to fame?
如果你想让我开心
Well, if you wanted to make me happy,
你可以跟我讲个笑话
you could have told me a joke.
或是给我看一段有爱的视频
Or shown me a cute video
比如考拉和水獭
of a koala and an otter
破天荒地成为朋友
becoming unlikely friends.
你总是最有理那个
Oh, there is no winning with you.
而且考拉和水獭居住地差了十万八千里
And koalas and otters don't even live near each other!
所以它们成为朋友才是破天荒之举
That's what makes their friendship unlikely!
你们俩在吵什么啊
What's with all the yelling?
莱纳德推翻了我的发现
Leonard disproved my element.
现在所有的关注都要消失了
Now all the attention is going to go away.
这很好啊  你一定很激动吧
Oh, that's great. You must be thrilled!
很好  我现在只剩七个朋友了
That's it! I'm down to seven friends.
他是连霍比特人和超级英雄都算上了吧
He's counting hobbits and superheroes, right?
一开始我以为元素是真实存在的  我不想要它
When I thought the element was real, I didn't want it.
但现在莱纳德证实它并不存在
But now that Leonard made it not exist,
它反而成了我全世界最想要的东西了
I want it more than anything in the world.
那元素从来就不存在
The-the element never existed.
不是我夺走它  而是科学夺走了它
I didn't take it away, science took it away.
要气就气科学吧
Be mad at science.
你胆敢用科学来反驳我
Don't you dare use science against me.
科学可是我最好的朋友
Science is my best friend!
太好了  我又有八个朋友了
Oh, good, I'm back up to eight.
你能告诉他  他疯了吗
Will you tell him he's out of his mind.
老实说  我理解他的意思
Actually, I get what he's saying.
太棒了  变九个了
Oh, yes! Nine!
欢迎回来  朋友
Welcome back, buddy.
就像跟一个你不是很喜欢的人约会
It's like if you're dating someone you're not that into,
等那人跟你分手了
and then they break up with you
你就变得很想要那人了
and then you want them more than ever.
我完全不知道她在说什么
I have no idea what she's talking about.
但我们现在联手对付你  所以我赞成她的话
but we're ganged up on you so I agree.
谢尔顿  那你要我怎么样
Okay, Sheldon, what do you want me to do,
隐瞒我的发现吗
hide the information?
如果我不公布
If I don't publish it,
迟早其他人也会这么做的
it's just a matter of time before someone else does.
不  你当然得公布
No, no, of course you have to publish.
那是你作为一个科学家应尽的责任
That's your responsibility as a scientist.
否则会违背职业道德
Doing otherwise would be unethical.
你别无选择
You have no choice.
好吧  我会公布
Fine, I'll publish.
你看这没良心的混球
Can you believe this guy?
拉杰把碗都洗了
Aw! Raj did the dishes.
你怎么知道不是我洗的
How do you know I didn't do them?
因为有一次  所有刀子都没洗
Because once, when all the knives were dirty,
你宁愿用钥匙切面包圈  也懒得洗
you cut a bagel with your keys.
早上好  两位
Good morning, everybody.
我出去的时候  顺便买了咖啡
I picked up coffee while I was out.
伯纳黛特  这是你的大豆薄荷摩卡
Bernadette, here's your soy peppermint mocha.
你真是太客气了
Aw, you didn't have to do that.
乐意之至
Oh, my pleasure,
对了  不要担心今天的演讲
and don't worry about your presentation today.
你一定会表现出色
You're gonna be great.
对啊  你一定能震惊四座
Yeah, you're gonna knock it out of the park.
我今天要做什么演讲来着
What presentation do I have today?
快走吧
Just go.
他很爱你的
He loves you.
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
你是故意让我难堪吗
Are you trying to make me look bad?
我只是想当个好客人
I'm just being a good house guest.
不  你是想当一个比我还好的丈夫
No, you're being a better husband than I am.
洗碗  买咖啡
Doing the dishes, getting coffee,
对她的生活了如指掌
knowing about her life--
谁会那样做啊
who does that?
别这样嘛  我也给你买了一杯
Oh, come on, I brought you one, too.
我不想喝咖啡
I don't want coffee.
所以我给你买了热巧克力
That's why I got you hot chocolate.
快给我
Give me that.
不许什么都做得比我好
Just stop showing me up.
霍华德  听我说
Howard, listen to me.
你是一个很棒的丈夫
You're a great husband.
没错  你倾听的技巧还需要多练练
Yes, your listening skills could use some work.
但作为一个独生子
But it's amazing how far you've come
还有一个过度保护的老妈
given that you're an only child
你算做得很不错啦
raised by an over-protective mom.
这情形好像有点奇怪啊
Um, is this getting weird?
别动
Hang on.
的确是很怪
So, yes.
我想告诉你一声  我发表了我的发现
I just wanted to let you know that I-I posted my findings.
我看见了
I saw.
我刚发公告  要求撤回我的论文
And I just posted a retraction of my paper.
现在整个科学界都知道我是错的
Now the whole scientific community knows I was wrong.
这样的事情经常发生  谢尔顿
These things happen all the time, Sheldon.
不是发生在我身上
Not to me.
我之前唯一一次公告的撤回说明
The only other retraction I ever had to issue
还是在我7岁的时候  我承认我哥哥
was when I was seven and I conceded that my brother
是东德州最优秀的忍者
was the greatest ninja in East Texas.
但那只是把我的脸
But that was just a ploy
从他的臭腋窝里拯救出来的权宜之计
to get my face out of his armpit.
他在这里啊
There he is!
我最爱的超级英雄
It's my favorite superhero--
撤回侠
the Retractor!
拜托  别落井下石了
Come on, don't give him a hard time.
对不起  库珀
I'm sorry, Cooper.
我撤回刚才说的话
I retract it.
顺便说下  霍夫斯塔德
By the way, Hofstadter,
做得真棒  推翻了中国研究组的结果
nice job disproving the Chinese team.
不算什么
It's not a big deal.
这可是大事
It's a huge deal.
库珀  也许你不太适合研究物理
Cooper, maybe physics just isn't your thing.
有没有考虑转去做零售
Have you ever considered a career in retail?
这样你就能靠撤回东西过生活了
That way you could take things back for a living.
好了  巴里  太过了
Okay, Barry, that's enough.
不  没事
Oh, no, that's okay.
我可以打赢自己的战斗
I can fight my own battles.
对吗  "八尼"
Isn't that right, "Bawwy."
你这是
Is...?
在嘲笑我的语言障碍吗
Is that a reference to my speech impediment?
太伤人了
That's pretty hurtful.
我
I...
我自己没法控制
I can't control it.
你说得对
You're right,
这招太卑鄙了
That was uncalled for.
我收回
I take it back.
你当然要收回了
Of course you do.
因为你是鼎鼎大名的撤回侠
Because you're the Retractor!
拉杰  晚餐的味道太好了
Raj, this dinner was amazing.
如果你多住一段时间
If you're here much longer,
我得买大一号的衣服了
I'm gonna have to buy bigger clothes.
瞎说
Nonsense.
你需要长点肉
You need a little fattening up.
你最近太瘦了
You've been looking too skinny lately.
华仔  你怎么从来不会说这些哄人开心的话
Howie, how come you never say anything sweet like that?
说什么呢
What are you talking about?
记得上周  我问你
Remember last week, when I asked you
你是否穿了塑身衣  你却没穿吗
if you were wearing Spanx and you weren't?
这明明就是夸你苗条嘛
How's that different?
也许你可以学学你的朋友拉杰
Maybe you could try being more thoughtful,
更体贴一些
like your friend Raj.
也许你可以学学拉杰
Yeah, well, maybe you could try being more like Raj.
-是吗  -当然
- Oh, really? - Yeah, yeah.
他今天早上为我打包了午餐
He packed me a lunch this morning.
袋子里有张字条写着  "勇敢上吧"
And there was a note inside that said, "Go get 'em"
我为这个家做得还不够多吗
Like I don't do enough around here.
现在还要为你打包午餐吗
Now I need to pack your lunch?
而且  你为什么需要字条来告诉你
And by the way, why do you need a note telling you
"勇敢上吧"  你是个大老爷们
to "Go get 'em"? You're a grown man!
你应该知道要"勇敢上吧"
You should know to "Go get 'em"!
我的确知道"勇敢上吧"
I do know to "Go get 'em"
只是有时候  我"勇敢"去"上"的同时
but sometimes it's nice to have emotional support
有精神支持感觉会更好
when I'm going and getting them!
别这样  瞧你们在说些什么话
Hey, hey, do you hear yourselves?
咱们冷静下  都各退一步
Let's just, you know, all calm down and take a step back.
太傻了  我们为什么要吵架
This is stupid. Why are we fighting?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想是因为我觉得自己是个差劲的老公
I guess I was just feeling like I'm a lousy husband.
你不是差劲的老公
You're not a lousy husband.
你是个非常棒的老公
You're a great husband.
我才觉得自己是个差劲的老婆
I was the one feeling like a lousy wife.
开什么玩笑  你最棒了
Are you kidding? You're the best.
我知道问题在哪里
I know what the problem is.
都怪他
It's him!
我做了什么
Oh, what did I do?
你让我们觉得  我们经营婚姻不够用心
You made us feel like we're not trying hard enough.
我们之前很满意我们打混摸鱼的婚姻
Yeah, we were totally fine half-assing our marriage
直到你这个祸害出现
till you showed up.
我很抱歉让你们生气了
Look, I'm sorry you're upset with me,
但我得说  看到你们统一战线
but I just have to say it's nice to see
真是太好了
the two of you on the same page.
你能支持我一次
Oh, it does feel good to have you
的确感觉不错
backing me up for once.
-我总是支持你好吧  -那不是...
－ I back you up all the time! - That is not...
-他又在挖坑  -你这人太坏了
- He's doing it again! - What is wrong with you?!
真不敢相信他们把你赶出来了
I can't believe they kicked you out.
真不敢相信他们还没离婚
I can't believe they're still married.
不好  我把小桂子的牙刷忘在霍华德家了
Oh, no, I forgot Cinnamon's toothbrush at Howard's.
看来你又要和爸比共用一把牙刷啦
I guess you're sharing with Daddy again.
要我打电话给反虐待动物协会就吠一声
Bark once if you need me to call PETA.
那只动物在咱们家干嘛
What's that animal doing in our apartment?
放轻松  她在笼子里  出不来的
Oh, relax, she's in her crate. She can't get out.
送你几个字送给你
I have two words for you:
侏罗纪公园[恐龙逃出]
Jurassic Park.
今天真是越来越糟糕
This day just keeps getting worse and worse.
如果这话能让你感觉好点...
You know, if it makes you feel any better...
可能不会
It probably won't.
你可能是对的
You're probably right.
谢尔顿  今晚夜色不错
Sheldon, it's a beautiful night.
我们出去散步好吗
Why don't you and I go for a nice walk together?
你这人怎么整天淫虫上脑啊
Oh, everything is just sex with you isn't it?
谢尔顿  你得意识到
Sheldon, I think you might find the support
想在恋爱中得到多少扶持
you're looking for, if you realize that
全取决于自己有多少付出
relationships are a give and take.
你有多支持她
She can only be there for you
她也会有多支持你
as much as you are for her.
谢谢你  拉杰什
Thank you, Rajesh.
艾米  你对待谢尔顿也要有耐心
And, Amy, you need to be patient with Sheldon,
而不是对他施压
instead of pressuring him
让他接受你的这一套亲密观
to accept intimacy on your terms.
你还是走人吧
You should probably go.
我是艾拉·菲莱  这里是《科学星期五》节目
I'm Ira Flatow, and this is Science Friday.
欢迎谢尔顿·库珀博士再次前来
I'd like to welcome back Dr. Sheldon Cooper,
他以为自己发现了一种新的超重元素
who thought he had discovered a new super-heavy element
不料却被另一位嘉宾莱纳德·霍夫斯塔德
only to have it disproved by my next guest,
证明是错的
Dr. Leonard Hofstadter.
先生们  欢迎来到《科学星期五》做客
Welcome to Science Friday, gentlemen.
-谢谢  -谢谢你
- Thanks. - Thank you.
艾拉  容我说一句  我想为
Ira, if I may, I'd like to apologize
我上周的行为道歉
for my behavior last week.
没关系
It's all right.
你有没有什么话想对我说
Now, isn't there something you'd like to say to me?
没有
No.
霍夫斯塔德博士
Now, Dr. Hofstadter.
你能讲述一遍你推翻
Can you walk us through the process
他理论的实验过程吗
you used to disprove his theory?
-好的  -我可以回答这个问题
- Well... - I believe I can answer that.
他问的是我
He asked me.
好的
Fine.
我刚才在说
As I was saying...
你讲得不好  艾拉
You're telling it wrong. Ira...
要想好好理解这件事
to really understand the story here,
就得从最开始讲起
you have to start at the very beginning:
在东德州的一个小镇  一位年幼的天才叫做
A small town in East Texas, where a young genius named...
-谢尔顿  -没错  谢尔顿·库珀
- Sheldon... - That's right, Sheldon Cooper.
他被邻居家的狗咬了
He was bitten by his neighbor's dog,
这让他有了第一次科学方面的大突破
leading to his first scientific breakthrough--
狗狗死亡射线
the doggie death-ray.
可悲的是  他不能使之成为现实
Which, sadly, he couldn't build
因为圣诞老人没有送他浓缩铀
because Santa wouldn't bring him enriched uranium.
你没意见的话  我真的很想听
I mean, I'd really like to hear it from Dr. Hofstadter,
霍夫斯塔德博士说说
if it's okay with you.
好意外啊
What a surprise.
你邀请我回来  就是为了无视我吗
Did-did you invite me back just so you could ignore me?
事实上  我根本没有邀请你
Actually, I didn't invite you.
你走进来  自己坐下
You came in, you took a seat,
我不太喜欢这种唇枪舌剑
and I'm not comfortable with confrontation.
谢尔顿  这次采访的重点是我
Sheldon, this interview is supposed to be about me.
听起来多无趣啊
Well, that seems like a snooze.
在无聊的电台上都显得无聊
Even for public radio.
如果他们每说一句丢人的话
You know, if we did a shot every time
我们就干一杯
they said something embarrassing,
那这游戏绝对能把人喝到酒精中毒
this would be one hell of a drinking game.
现在喝酒太早了吧
A little early for alcohol, isn't it?
我可不仅只会发表科学方面的高明见解
You know, I don't just say smart things about science.
我还会唱山歌
I also yodel.
我去拿伏特加
I'll get the vodka.